petflow.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy | Petflow.com

* Privacy Policy. 

Welcome to the PetFlow® website located at www.petflow.com (the “Site”). The Site is an Internet property of PetFlow (“PetFlow®,” “we,” “our” or “us”). The information we collect through our Site helps us provide you with information specific to your needs and interests. Please read below to review our PetFlow® Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) and the types of information we gather through our Site. You agree to this Privacy Policy in its entirety when you: (a) access or use the Site; (b) access and/or view any of the videos, audio, stories, testimonials, text, photographs, graphics, artwork and/or other content featured on the Site (collectively, the “Content”); (c) access links to PetFlow’s® social media pages/accounts on third party social media websites, such as Facebook® and Instagram® (collectively, “Social Media Pages”); (d) utilize the website contact form and/or other functionality as a means to make inquiries and/or request being contacted by PetFlow® (collectively, “Contact Services”); (e) sign up to participate in PetFlow’s® Refer-a-Friend program (“Refer-a-Friend Program”); (f) utilize our pet store finder to locate participating pets stores and related retail establishments near your designated location (“Pet Store Finder”); and/or (g) purchase any of the pet-related products and/or services made available by and through the Site (collectively, the “Product(s)” and together with the Site, Content, Social Media Pages, Contact Services, Refer-a-Friend Program and Pet Store Finder, the “PetFlow® Offerings”). 

All capitalized terms not defined in this Privacy Policy shall have the meanings ascribed to them in the PetFlow® Terms of Service (“TOS”). **IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY IN THEIR ENTIRETY, YOU MAY NOT ACCESS OR OTHERWISE USE THE PETFLOW® OFFERINGS.**

_Facebook® and Instagram® are registered trademarks of Facebook, Inc. (“Facebook”). Please be advised that PetFlow® is not in any way affiliated with Facebook, and the PetFlow® Offerings are not endorsed, administered or sponsored by Facebook._

* Your California Privacy Rights 

If you are a resident of the State of California and would like to learn how your “personal information” (as defined in the Shine the Light Law, Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.83) is shared with third parties, what categories of personal information that we have shared with third parties in the preceding year, as well as the names and addresses of those third parties, please e-mail us at: [help@petflow.com](mailto:help@petflow.com); send us correspondence to: PetFlow, 989 6th Avenue, 12th Floor, New York, NY 10018; or telephone us at: (888) 316-7297. 

Further, if you are a resident of the State of California and would like to opt-out from the disclosure of your personal information to any third party for marketing purposes, please e-mail us at: [help@petflow.com](mailto:help@petflow.com); send us correspondence to: PetFlow, 989 6th Avenue, 12th Floor, New York, NY 10018; or telephone us at: (888) 316-7297. Please be advised that where California State residents opt-out from permitting their personal information to be shared, such individuals may still receive selected offers directly from us, in accordance with applicable law. 

* How Does Petflow Gather and Use Information? 

  1. Cookies. Cookies are pieces of data assigned by a web server that uniquely identify the browser on your PC. Websites typically use temporary cookies called “session“ cookies to ensure that you are recognized when you move from page to page within one website and that any information that you have entered is remembered. For example, if an e-commerce website did not use session cookies, then items placed in a shopping basket would disappear by the time you reach the checkout. Websites also use cookies called “persistent“ cookies to enable a website to remember you on subsequent visits, thereby speeding up or enhancing your experience of services or functions offered. To find out more about Cookies, please visit www.cookiecentral.com.

PetFlow® may install both persistent and session cookies when an end-user arrives at the Site. Cookies enable our systems to gather information about your navigational patterns through the Site. End-users have the option to accept or disable cookies at any time through their Internet browsers. Visit the “help” portion of your Internet browser’s toolbar for more information. If you block or refuse to accept cookies, or delete cookies between visits to the Site, you may not be able to access or use certain features or functions of the PetFlow® Offerings. We reserve the right to retain Cookie data indefinitely. 

  2. Server Statistics. We collect general statistics to track end-user trends on our Site. These statistics include hits to our server, the types of Internet browsers used to access our Site (e.g., Safari, Chrome, Internet Explorer), page views, navigational patterns, end-user IP addresses, the type of operating system that our end-users use (e.g., Windows or iOS) and the domain names of our end-users’ Internet service provider (e.g., Verizon, AT&T). The information that is collected in this manner does NOT provide us with any personally identifiable information about our end-users. It helps us track “where” our end-users are coming from. This allows us to pinpoint high traffic areas and determine the most effective ways to communicate with our end-users. We use the non-personally identifiable information that we collect to improve the design and content of the PetFlow® Offerings and to enable us to personalize your Internet experience. We also may use this information in the aggregate to analyze usage of the PetFlow® Offerings. As part of that ongoing analysis, PetFlow® also uses devices called “web beacons” (also known as a “clear gifs” or a “pixel tags”). These beacons/tags are 1x1 pixel images embedded in a website page that are used to transparently collect information. We may use these beacons/tags to count the number of times that visitors click on a particular banner ad or visit the pages of the Site and/or to help us identify when e-mails sent to you have been received and read, as applicable, and to provide information about what products/services are viewed or purchased. We reserve the right to retain this beacon/tag data indefinitely.

  3. Personal Information You Provide Us. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, “Personal Information” is any information that identifies you, that would enable someone to contact you or that describes your relationship with PetFlow®. We collect and store Personal Information when you register to use our Site, ask a question, complete a form, conduct a transaction, or send us an e-mail. While you are not required to submit any information on our Site, if you do not provide the requested information, you may not be able to access or use some of the features and functions of the PetFlow® Offerings and we may not be able to accommodate certain requests. Depending on the PetFlow® Offerings requested by you, PetFlow® will collect some or all of the following: (i) your full name; (ii) your e-mail address; (iii) your billing/mailing address; (iv) your telephone number; (v) your credit card information (where you wish to purchase Products); and/or (vi) any other information requested on the applicable form. For purposes of this Privacy Policy, item (v) in the preceding sentence shall be referred to as “Sensitive Information.” 

PetFlow® uses your Personal Information to complete transactions, respond to your requests and inquiries, deliver the Products and services you request, for customer service functions and to notify you of PetFlow® and/or third party-related promotions, updates, marketing messages or special offers that we think may be of interest to you. If you are already receiving PetFlow® e-mails and no longer wish to receive such communications, simply follow the "unsubscribe" instructions that appear in every PetFlow® e-mail, or contact us through the preference center to modify subscriptions. We may also use your Personal Information for internal business purposes, such as analyzing and managing our service offerings including, without limitation, the PetFlow® Offerings. We may also combine the information we have gathered about you with information from other sources. 

By submitting your Personal Information by and through the PetFlow® Offerings, you agree that such act constitutes an inquiry and/or application for purposes of the Amended Telemarketing Sales Rule (16 CFR §310 et seq.), as amended from time to time (the “Rule”) and applicable state do-not-call regulations. As such, notwithstanding that your telephone number may be listed on the Federal Trade Commission’s Do-Not-Call List, and/or on applicable state do-not-call lists, we retain the right to contact you via telemarketing in accordance with the Rule and applicable state do-not-call regulations. 

Where you provide “prior express written consent” within the meaning of the Telephone Consumer Protection Act (47 USC § 227), and its implementing regulations adopted by the Federal Communications Commission (47 CFR § 64.1200), as amended from time-to-time (“TCPA”), you consent to receive telephone calls from PetFlow®, including artificial voice calls, pre-recorded messages and/or calls (including SMS text messages) delivered via automated technology, to the telephone number(s) that you provided. Please note that you are not required to provide this consent in order to obtain access to the PetFlow® Offerings, and your consent simply allows PetFlow® to contact you via these means. **Please be advised that by agreeing to this Privacy Policy, you are obligated to immediately inform us if and when the telephone number that you have previously provided to us changes. Without limiting the foregoing, if you: (A) have your telephone number reassigned to another person or entity; (B) give up your telephone number so that it is no longer used by you; (C) port your telephone number to a landline or vice versa; or (D) otherwise stop using that telephone number for any reason (collectively “Phone Number Change”), you agree that you shall promptly notify PetFlow® of the Phone Number Change via e-mail at:[help@petflow.com](mailto:help@petflow.com), or by using one of the methods set forth in the “Contact Us” section below.**

  4. Behavioral Tracking. PetFlow® uses cookies and other tracking technology on the Site for purposes of tracking end-users’ activities after they leave the Site. PetFlow® uses these cookies to target applicable end-users with advertisements regarding the PetFlow® Offerings and other products and/or services that PetFlow® thinks may be of interest to applicable end-users. In addition, third parties such as Google, Inc. may engage in a similar form of behavioral tracking of end-users that visit the Site. End-users may be able to disable some, but not all, of this tracking activity by utilizing the “Do Not Track” setting or similar options within most major Internet browsers. To the greatest extent permissible under applicable law, we are not responsible for the tracking practices of third parties in connection with the Site. 

* What Security Procedures does PetFlow® Use to Protect Personal Information? 

We endeavor to safeguard and protect our end-users’ Personal Information. When end-users make Personal Information available to us, their Personal Information is protected both online and offline (to the extent that we maintain any Personal Information offline). Where our registration/application process prompts end-users to enter Sensitive Information, and when we store and transmit such Sensitive Information, that information is encrypted with advanced TLS (Transport Layer Security) technology. 

Access to your Personal Information is strictly limited, and we take reasonable measures to ensure that your Personal Information is not accessible to the public. All of our end-users’ Personal Information is restricted in our offices, as well as the offices of our third party service providers. Only employees or third party agents who need Personal Information to perform a specific job are granted access to Personal Information. Our employees are dedicated to ensuring the security and privacy of all end-user Personal Information. Employees not adhering to our firm policies are subject to disciplinary action. The servers that we store Personal Information on are kept in a secure physical environment. We also have security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of Personal Information under our control. 

Please be advised, however, that while we take every reasonable precaution available to protect your data, no storage facility, technology, software, security protocols or data transmission over the Internet or via wireless networks can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Computer hackers that circumvent our security measures may gain access to certain portions of your Personal Information, and technological bugs, errors and glitches may cause inadvertent disclosures of your Personal Information; provided, however, that any attempt to breach the security of the network, our servers, databases or other hardware or software may constitute a crime punishable by law. For the reasons mentioned above, we cannot warrant that your Personal Information will be absolutely secure. Any transmission of data at or through the Site, other PetFlow® Offerings or otherwise via the Internet or wireless network, is done at your own risk. 

In compliance with applicable federal and state laws, we shall notify you and any applicable regulatory agencies in the event that we learn of an information security breach with respect to your Personal Information. You will be notified via e-mail in the event of such a breach. Please be advised that notice may be delayed in order to address the needs of law enforcement, determine the scope of network damage, and to engage in remedial measures. 

* Will Petflow Disclose The Information It Collects To Outside Parties? 

We may share your information, including Personal Information, to third parties, as set forth below:

  1. Agents, Consultants and Related Third Parties: We, like many businesses, sometimes hire other companies to perform certain business-related functions. Examples include mailing information, maintaining databases and processing payments. When we employ another company to perform a function of this nature, we only provide them with the information that they need to perform their specific function.

  2. Advertisers: We may aggregate Personal Information with Personal Information of other users of the site, and disclose such information in a non-personally, or personally identifiable manner to advertisers and other third parties for marketing and promotional purposes. In these situations, we may disclose to these entities any information that could be used to identify you personally.

  3. Legal Requirements: We may disclose Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) comply with a legal obligation, (b) protect and defend our rights or property, (c) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of the Site or the public, or (d) protect against legal liability.

  4. Business Transfers: As we develop our business, we might sell or buy businesses or assets. In the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution or similar event, Personal Information may be part of the transferred assets.

* External Links. 

Other companies or organizations may have links to their web sites on the Site. We are not responsible for how these other companies or organizations collect, use, disclose, or secure the information that you provide them. If you choose to access a third party web site linked to from the Site, you do so at your own risk and subject to any terms of service or privacy policy (if any) associated with such third party web site.

* Collection Of Information From Children. 

We do not direct any of our content specifically to children. Users of the Site are required to be at least 18 years old, and any user under 18 is not an authorized user. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s Internet usage and to instruct their children to never provide Personal Information though this Site or any other web site without their permission. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 18 has provided Personal Information to us through the Site, please contact us and we will endeavor to delete any Personal Information we have collected about that user.

* Removal, Amending and/or Updating Your Information. 

At your request, we will: (a) inform you of what Personal Information we have on file for you; (b) amend the Personal Information that we have on file for you; and/or (c) remove Personal Information that you have provided to us, or that we have collected. You may do so by contacting us via e-mail at: [help@petflow.com](mailto:help@petflow.com); provided, however, that we ask individuals to identify themselves and the information requested to be accessed, amended or removed before processing such requests and, to the extent permitted by applicable law, we may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup tapes). 

Please be advised that, after you delete your Personal Information, residual copies may take a period of time before they are deleted from our active servers and may remain in our backup systems. 

* Opt-out/Unsubscribe 

To opt-out of receiving e-mail communications from us, you can follow the instructions at the end of the applicable e-mail message or e-mail us at: [help@petflow.com](mailto:help@petflow.com). 

Notwithstanding the foregoing, we may continue to contact you for the purpose of communicating information relating to your request for PetFlow® Offerings, as well as to respond to any inquiry or request made by you. To opt-out of receiving PetFlow® Offerings-related and/or inquiry response-related messages from PetFlow®, you must cease requesting and/or utilizing the PetFlow® Offerings and/or cease submitting inquiries to PetFlow®, as applicable. 

* Consent To Processing In The United States. 

If you are visiting the Site from a country other than the country in which our servers are located, your communications with us may result in the transfer of information across international boundaries. By providing any Personal Information to us, all end-users including, without limitation, end-users in Canada and the member states of the European Union, fully understand and unambiguously consent to this Privacy Policy and to the transfer of such Personal Information across international borders in accordance with PetFlow’s® standard operations, including the collection, storage, and processing of such information in the United States of America. Even if your jurisdiction does not have the same privacy laws as the jurisdiction where our servers are located, we will treat your information as subject to the protections described in this Privacy Policy.

* Modification And Notification Of Changes. 

We may at our sole discretion edit this Privacy Policy. Notice of all changes to the Privacy Policy will be provided as specified in Section 12 (Modification and Notification of Changes) of the Terms of Service.

* Filing a Complaint with the Federal Trade Commission. 

To file a complaint regarding our privacy practices, please [Click Here](https://www.ftccomplaintassistant.gov/FTC_Wizard.aspx?Lang=en).

* How to Contact Us. 

If you have questions or suggestions regarding this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices please visit our support page at www.petflow.com/support.

Or mail us at:  

_PetFlow  
989 6th Avenue, Floor 12  
New York, NY 10018  
_
